<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy on GregTech</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on GregTech</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chat Control, the Privacy Nightmare That Keeps Coming Back</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chatcontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chatcontrol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a 13-year-old student from Slovenia. I care about privacy and my future as an EU citizen, and currently the future is looking bleak. Wars, even more wars, homelessness, late stage capitalism and privacy nightmares.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-chat-control&#34;&gt;&#xA;  What is chat control?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#what-is-chat-control&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chat control is a method that the European Commission has proposed for monitoring online communication. This is the third time they have attempted to implement it. It involves requiring technology companies to scan all chat messages and report them. While it has not yet been implemented, there is currently a law in place that allows providers to scan your messages. This is optional, so they are not forced to do so. It is worth noting that only a few unencrypted communication providers currently engage in this type of scanning, including Skype, Snapchat, Gmail, Facebook and Instagram Messenger, iCloud email and Xbox. Even end-to-end encrypted messaging apps would not be excluded from chat control, which could potentially undermine the entire point of it. The EU Commission also plans to include mandatory age verification, which would make anonymity harder to achieve&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
